Oscar(Wei Chieh) Chen

Address: 10F, No.48, Zhong Xing Rd Sec.1, Shin Dian District, New Taipei City

Oscar is a graduate from the Department of Statistics in National Taipei University, with expertise in big data analysis (python, R, SAS), Design and Analysis of Clinical Trials, High Dimensional Data Analysis, Time Series Analysis, and Survival Analysis. His exposure to international education background in Singapore and Beijing made him an easy addition to any team and well-suited to collaborative work environment.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

National Taipei University- Bachelor of Statistics	2017-2020
Fu Jen Catholic University - Bachelor of Statistics and Information Science	2017-2020

LEADERSHIP ACHIEVEMENT

Vice President- National Taipei University Softball Team

2018-2020

- Personal Achievement: the 40th National Statistics Cup Lifetime Achievement Award
- Led the team to win in National Statistics Cup- 2018 Champion, 2019 2nd Runner-up and 2020 runner up awards
- Led the team to win in National Mathematics Cup (North Taiwan Division)- 2019 & 2020 Runner up
- Led the team to win in National Taipei University softball League- 2019 & 2020 Champion

AWARDS

Honorable Award - National Taipei University Statistical Project Competition

May 2020

- Topic: Case study of relationship between salaries and performance in USA Major League Baseball and Chinese Professional Baseball League
- Statistical Software: SAS, R

Abstract: Using the data of Major League Baseball from 1985 to 2016 to execute machine learning algorithms and regression analysis to select important variables in order to establish salary prediction models. The salary prediction model can be applied to the cost management and player risk assessment of franchises in Major League Baseball and Chinese Professional Baseball League. The tool is effective in helping franchise to optimize the operating profit.

National Taipei University Representative Team - 1st Al FinTech Association Innovation Idea Tournament

Oct 2019

- Topic: Evaluate the investment potential of user data on Steam for game developers
- Concept: Combining cloud data from various websites, via API Just-in-time access and analyzing by the system to score each game.
- Market Potential: This system can be used by connecting to the internet, and targets to young generation. With appropriate media exposure,
 it can attract investors who are interested in the game industry.
- Overall Planning: Integrate the system into an application. When users browse the analysis results, attaching links to the game platform, broadcasting platform and trading platform to attract stable views.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staff & Play-by-play broadcaster- Chinese Professional Baseball League

Mar. 2019-now

- Live streaming productions and writing to provide game insights through online live play-by-play broadcasting
- English translator for all foreign players and spectators

Teacher Assistant- KaoWei Mathematics Institution

Jun. 2016-Jan. 2017

- Arranged scheduling for 200+ students
- Provided consultation to solve math question for 20+ students

SPECIAL SKILLS

- Language: Mandarin (Fluent), English (Fluent), French (Basic)
- Computer Skill: C++, LaTEX, MATLAB, Microsoft Office, Visual Basic, Python, R, SAS, SQL